(嚴禁入內）
你要去哪裡？
It's got to lead somewhere.
嗯，我們馬上就紮營，上氣不接下氣嗎？
Well, we'll stop and make camp  pretty soon. Got your breath?
是啊，走吧
Yeah. Let's go.
這是什麼地方？
What is this?
以前肯定有人呆過，我們進去看看
It doesn't look like anyone's been here for  a while. Let's go inside and check it out.
- 真的要進去嗎？ - 芭芭拉，沒事的
- Think we should?  - Barbara, who'd know the difference?
好吧
OK.
進來吧，沒有背包很容易過來
Besides, a little lawbreaking'll  do you good.
你的地圖上沒有這個地方
Wonder why this place  wasn't on your map.
可能是個秘密的地方
Maybe it's  supposed to be a secret.
可能是
Maybe.
嘿！
Hey!
游泳池！
Far out!
感覺好極了
It feels great.
我們洗澡吧，然後好好睡個覺
Come on, let's wash off, so it won't  be so funky in that sleeping bag.
有人會看見的
What if somebody catches us?
有誰會看見？
Who's gonna catch us?
這裡沒有人
There's nobody here.
我們洗澡吧
Let's get wet.
- 看誰先脫完 - 我從沒幹過這種事
- Last one in is a rotten egg.  - That's really original.
- 等等 - 什麼？
- Wait a minute.  - What?
萬一這裡是污水處理廠呢？
What if this is some kind  of a sewage treatment plant?
白癡
Idiot.
你又搗鬼
Now you're gonna get it.
感覺怎麼樣？
How is it?
我來了
Here I come.
- 這不好笑 - 什麼？
- That's not funny.  - What?
你咬我，不敢相信你咬我
You bit me. I can't believe  you actually bit me.
我看起來像巫婆嗎？
What do I look like?  A creature from the black lagoon?
你是患多疑症吧，不要開玩笑了
You are paranoid, kid. Listen,  I'll race you to the deep end.
芭芭拉！水裡面有東西
Barbara! There's something in here!
大衛！
David!
他媽的！
God damn!
大衛！
David!
大衛?
David?
大衛！
David!
大衛！ 大衛！
David! David!
《食人魚》
- 坐吉普車去嗎？ - 我們走的是沒有鋪過的山路
- Rent a Jeep?  - She'll be on unpaved mountain roads...
好吧，我簽字
All right. Where do I sign?
你到了印第安泉會有吉普車在那兒等你 那邊的路非常顛簸
We're all set. At lndian Springs you'll get  a Jeep. The roads are very rough there.
沒事
No sweat.
- 我可以搞定的 - 我知道
- I can handle it.  - I know.
不然的話就不派你去了
I wouldn't send you if  I didn't think you could.
等一下，好了
Wait. Got ya.
- 我先到印第安泉 - 對
- I found the bigamist.  - Right.
- 那裡有吉普車在等我？ - 對
- And the bad-cheque lady?  - Right.
- 而且路很顛簸 - 是的，那是個小鎮
- And Mo Schneider.  - Three times, but those were all in town.
而你是在城市裡長大 而那邊是一座大山
You're a city kid.  These kids are out in the boon...
我什麼都能找到，我的前生是一條偵探犬
I can find anything, Earl.  I'm two-thirds bloodhound.
你僱傭我的時候我告訴過你
I told you that when you hired me.
哦，天吶，我的票呢？我放在口袋裡了
Oh, my gosh. My ticket. I could  have sworn I put it in my pocket.
我的票跑哪裡去了？
Where's my ticket?
- 我完全可以搞定 - 你當然可以
- I can manage it.  - Of course you can.
- 往銀行存錢 - 那可是我的錢
- It's money in the bank.  - My money.
布蘭迪，你好啊
Hello, Brandy. How are you, huh?
去一趟城裡要花我越來越多的時間了
This hike from town is  gettin' longer every week.
- 你得弄輛車，傑克 - 我有車
- You oughta get a car, Jack.  - I got a car.
這地方車用不了多久
It's up on blocks. That's where it belongs.
蘇格蘭威士忌
Scotch.
杜松子酒
Gin.
奔農酒
Bourbon.
還有哈奇拉酒！
Tequila!
你真是雪中送炭啊，傑克
You're the 7th Cavalry, Jack.
你知道我的酒正好快沒了
You know, I just ran dry today.
那邊有燕麥片，可我不願上那裡去拿
Your corn meal is down there, but  I ain't gonna walk down and get it.
光喝酒我可活不了
Man cannot live by booze alone.
全都給你吧，夠了嗎？
In lieu of rent. What's up in town?
- 鎮裡情況怎麼樣？ - 和以前一樣
- Same as usual.  - I bet you miss it, Jack, huh?
我想你肯定想到鎮上去居住吧？ 那邊生活方便多了
I bet you miss sellin' whatever  it was. That plastic fruit.
不
No.
看看這河
Got the river.
每天早上起來
It wakes me up in the morning.
讓人心曠神怡
Gives me a bath.
還有我的小屋
Does the laundry.
還有我的晚餐 晚上睡覺也特別安靜
Gives me my dinner.  Puts me to sleep real gentle.
還有樹林
I got my river.
還有布蘭迪
I got Brandy.
一切都有了
Paul.
你有什麼呢？
What have you got up here?
我有蘇格蘭威士忌，杜松子酒，奔農酒，還有哈奇拉酒
I got scotch, gin, bourbon, and tequila.
- 這些足夠了吧？ - 很好
- What's it to you, anyhow?  - OK.
好了，夥計，再見
OK, buddy. I'll see you.
跟上，布蘭迪
Come on.
悠著點，布蘭迪
Take it easy, Brandy.
哇！
Ow!
嗯
Hm.
門開著
It's open.
你是保羅 格羅根嗎？
Paul Grogan?
你好，我叫瑪吉.邁克歐文 是為一家找人公司工作的
Hi. I'm Maggie McKeown.  I work for a skip-tracing company.
- 什麼公司？ - 我們查找失蹤人口
- What's that?  - We find missing people.
是我前妻叫你來的嗎？
Did my ex-wife send you?
不
No.
嗯
Um...
我找兩個年輕人
I'm looking for a pair of teenage kids.
他們的朋友說他們可能來這兒旅行了
Some friends said they might  be backpacking up here.
我沒看見他們，你找別人去問吧
I haven't seen 'em. Did you  talk to the sheriff's people?
- 他們說這是一座大山 - 對，確實如此
- They said it was a big mountain.  - They're right. It is.
我猜他們是沿著河走的，這附近有游泳的地方嗎？
I figured they may have followed the river.  Are there any places to swim near here?
如果他們被淹死了，肯定被衝到大壩去了
Well, if they'd drowned,  they'd be swept down to the dam.
你找錯地方了
So you're startin' at the wrong end.
可能只是找錯人了吧
Boy, you're the wrong end all right.
我是不是打攪你了？ 但我這是很重要的事情
Look, am I interrupting something?  This is kind of important.
嘿
Hey,
你說話口氣不太對，女士
you cool your jets, lady.
我沒有殺人，我幫不了你，因為我沒見過他們
I didn't axe-murder your young couple.  I can't help you. I haven't seen 'em.
這兒附近有什麼棚屋嗎？
Are there any other shacks up here?
只有茅屋，這就是個茅屋
Cabins. This is a cabin.
還有沒有別的？他們可能被綁架在哪兒了？
Are there any more of them? Any places  where they might be holed up?
一個叫傑克的老傢伙在河邊有一個小木屋
There's an old fella named Jack,  has a place down the river a bit,
不過也沒聽說有什麼年輕人來過
but he's not with them.
不過在山頂上有個軍方實驗室
And there was some kind of army  test site way up the mountain.
- 只是已經關閉五六年了 - 那好，我們走吧
- That closed down five or six years ago.  - Come on. Let's go.
- 去哪兒？ - 你帶我去你說的地方
- Go where?  - You're taking me up there.
我不去
Oh, no, I'm not.
你覺得我是在浪費我的時間嗎？
You think I'm wasting my time, don't you?
才不是，你是在浪費我的時間
No. I think you're wastin' my time.
- 發現什麼了嗎？ - 還沒有，不過現在天還早
- Find anything yet?  - Not yet, but it's still early in the day.
大衛！
David!
芭芭拉！
Barbara!
- 軍方在這裡做什麼試驗？ - 天知道
- What were they testing here?  - Who knows?
我和前妻曾來過一次
I hiked up here once with my ex-wife.  They had guard dogs out.
那時籬笆都裝上了電網
The fence was electrified. The works.
BR. 芭芭拉.蘭多夫
"BR." Barbara Randolph.
嗯
Hm.
水好冷
Man, that is cold.
他們的父母說他們的水性都不錯
Their parents said they  were excellent swimmers.
他們不會現在才浮起來吧？
Wouldn't they be floatin'  up on top by now?
屍體浮上來需要一段時間
It takes a while for  the body to bloat with gas.
你還挺專業的
Nice business you're in.
這池塘有沒有放水塞子呢？
You think there's a way  to pull the plug on this?
- 熱帶魚？ - 看上去像是實驗用的
- Tropical fish?  - Looks like it's for laboratory rats.
訓練他們穿越障礙找到食物
You know, where they had to get through  an obstacle course to get a reward.
嗯
Hm.
還是熱的
Still warm.
過來，快看這個
Come here. Take a look at this.
噁心
Yeuch.
我們走吧，這地方讓我毛骨悚然
Let's get outta here.  This place gives me the creeps.
嘿！你幹什麼…
Hey! What are you...
他們來過這兒，沒錯
Well, they've been here all right.
而且沒有離開
And they never left.
- 我要把池塘的水全部放掉 - 可是沒有人允許
- I say we drain the pond.  - Well, now. Now, wait a minute.
你是不能這樣做的
You can't do that without gettin'  somebody's permission, you know.
這是我們解決問題最快的辦法
If it works it's the quickest way  to know if they're down there.
天吶，你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
你沒事吧？
Are you all right?
- 他還活著嗎 - 他還有氣
- He's breathing.  - No thanks to you.
- 都怪你，該怎麼辦，我有任務在身 - 反正我又不會怪你
- What was I supposed to do?  - I would have got loose in a second.
- 我的酒壺都被你打壞了 - 能讓我喝口水嗎？
- Look at this. You put a dent in it.  - Could I have a sip of that, please?
那不是水
It's not water.
- 怎麼樣？ - 有點鹹
- What is it?  - The water's salty.
這個池塘的水會放到哪兒去？
Where does this drain to?
軍方接管之前，這個池塘是孵化魚苗用的
It was a fish hatchery  before the army took it over.
也許是放到河裡去了
It probably drains  underground into the river.
啊噢
Uh-oh.
可能是條狗，可它怎麼會掉到這兒來
I think it's a dog. I don't suppose  they would have fit through here.
一點肉也不剩
Not in one piece.
你覺得剛才那個人還在那兒嗎？
You think he's all right up there?
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我肯定是忘了拔鑰匙
I guess I must have left  the keys in it. Huh?
- 他還活著 - 他真命大
- He's alive.  - He's indestructible.
別怕，別怕，沒事
Easy. Easy, now. Easy. Easy.
- 你闖禍了 - 我闖了什麼禍？
- Razorteeth.  - What's "razorteeth"?
- 你把池塘的水放了？ - 是的…
- You drained the pond?  - Yes...
- 它們出來了 - 什麼出來了？
- You let them out?  - Let who out?
沒事吧？
What's he doin'?
你們不知道，現在事情鬧大了
You don't know what  you've done. Untie me.
我的問題是，你自己幹了什麼
The question is, what you've done, mister.
你不明白
You don't know.
它們非常聰明，你們鬥不過它們的
They breed like flies.  There'll be no way to stop them.
冷靜點好嗎？那兩個孩子呢？
Would you talk sense, dammit?  What about those kids?
我不能告訴你，它們會殺光我們的
I can't tell you. Mother of God,  they'll kill us. They'll kill all of us.
先生，聽著，你還是好好休息吧
OK, mister, listen. They're gonna  sweat it out of you in town.
它們會殺了我們的
They'll kill us.
我們都做了些什麼？
What have we done?
哦，上帝啊
Oh, my God.
- 他說會有什麼東西來殺他 - 有可能
- He thinks someone's going to kill him.  - He's right.
他是犯了多疑症吧
I am, if he steps out of line.
- 給我一支煙好嗎？ - 沒有
- Do you have any cigarettes?  - No.
一年前戒了，我現在只喝酒
I quit a year ago.  It interfered with my drinking.
我進來呆一會兒行嗎？
Do you mind if I come in for a minute?
當然可以
Sure.
你是在那之前還是在那之後開始喝酒的？
So, did you start drinking before or after?
- 什麼之前之後？ - 你妻子離開你
- Before or after what?  - Your wife left you.
- 這算是個什麼問題？ - 對不起，我只是有點感興趣而已
- What the hell kind of question is that?  - Look, I'm sorry. I was just interested.
嗯
Um,
我坐這兒行嗎？
do you mind if I sit here?
坐吧
Go ahead.
- 你結婚多久了 - 嗯？
- How long were you married?  - Huh?
Um,
十年
ten years.
我們十七歲時就在父親的車中相愛了
She was just 1 7 when we  eloped in her father's car.
然後就結婚了
Man, we thought we had  the world by the balls.
你住在哪兒？
Where did you live?
小鎮上，本來我在河邊辦了個工廠
In town. I worked in  a smeltin' operation downriver.
可是被政府關閉了，說那對河裡的魚有影響
The government closed us down.  Said we killed too many fish.
他們把工廠給了軍隊，軍隊又賣給了別人
They gave it to the army, and the  army sold it to some resort ouftit.
有人在用我原來的地方大發其財
So you know that somebody's makin'  bundles somewheres along the line.
那你現在以什麼為生？
How do you make a living now?
我做一些零工
Back pay. Unemployment.
九月份就有活幹了
Gonna have to go to work  come September.
還要照顧我女兒蘇珊
Keep my daughter in saddle shoes.
- 你女兒和你住在一起嗎？ - 對
- Does your daughter live with you?  - Yeah.
- 怎麼了？ - 嗯？
- What's wrong?  - Hm?
- 你好像很緊張 - 嗯？
- You're so tense.  - Hm?
我不知道，我習慣了一個人
I don't know. I guess I'm not  used to bein' around people.
本來說進來呆一會兒的，現在待了這麼久
That's obvious. I've been trying to hint  my way under the covers for five minutes.
沒事
You are really somethin'.
沒有了你的吉普車，我們很難出去的
There's no way we're gonna get  this guy down to town without your Jeep.
可我們要採取點行動，他的顱骨已經破裂了
We have to do something.  He might have fractured his skull.
我們把他帶到大壩那邊去 對不起，讓你久等了
We gotta get him to the dam.  There's usually a ranger there.
- 我們怎麼去呢？ - 木筏
- How do we get there?  - On a raft.
- 別開玩笑了，我們到底怎麼去 - 你會知道的
- Stop kidding. How do we get there?  - You'll see.
我去年夏天看了我女兒的「哈克貝利.費恩歷險記」
I read my daughter  Huckleberry Finn last summer.
上面就有坐木筏歷險的描述，這是唯一出去的辦法
We wanted to light out for the territories  so we settled on this as a compromise.
- 看上去做的挺結實 - 是啊，木頭都是我自己砍的
- It looks authentic.  - Yeah. We cut all the logs ourselves.
每個釘子都是我敲進去的，非常結實
Not a single nail in her. It's all lashing.
- 你女兒現在在哪兒？ - 大壩旁的一個夏令營
- Where's your daughter now?  - Summer camp, other side of the dam.
這東西真不穩
Just how sturdy is this thing?
可以坐三個人
I think it'll hold three people.
不過告訴你實話，我也沒坐過 我女兒有恐水症
To tell you the truth, we never tried it.  My daughter's afraid of the river.
Boys are made of greasy grimy gopher guts！
Boys are made  of greasy grimy gopher guts
Mutilated monkey meat！
Mutilated monkey meat
Little dirty birdie feet！
Little dirty birdie feet
Sneezed-up snail snot！
Sneezed-up snail snot
Bashed-in beetles' brains！
Bashed-in beetles' brains
All in a bottle of blood！
All in a bottle of blood
蘇珊 蘇珊 寶貝，不要害怕
Suzie? Suzie, honey, don't be scared.
你只要游過去然後再游回來
You just have to swim out  to the marker and back.
如果在游泳池裡，你可以游這兩倍的距離
You've probably swum  twice that far in a pool.
如果你不能通過單人游泳考試的話 你就得不到水上徽章
If you don't pass your solo swim  you can't get your water badge.
拿不到就算了
I don't care.
你到底怕什麼呢，親愛的？
What is it that you're afraid of, honey?
- 水裡的東西 - 你是說海怪嗎？
- Things.  - You mean like sea monsters?
這兒只有一些小魚
There's just a few little fish in here.
在河底的水草裡
They eat plants at the bottom of the river.
它們只會親親你的小手指和小腳趾
They're not interested  in little girls' fingers and toes.
- 迪金森！ - 在這兒，杜蒙特先生
Dickinson!  - Dickinson!  - Over here, Mr Dumont.
有你的信，迪金森，又是那個男孩
Letter for you, Dickinson. That same boy.
哦，謝謝你
Oh, thank you.
你還是不敢下河游泳嗎？蘇珊
Still haven't tackled  your solo swim, Grogan?
是的
No, sir.
她怕水裡的東西
She's kind of afraid of things in the water.
東西，什麼東西？小魚嗎？ 人是吃魚的，可魚不吃人
Things? What things? Fish? People eat  fish, Grogan. Fish don't eat people.
你想輸掉夏令營競賽嗎？
Do you wanna be the one to lose the  camp competition for the Minnows?
當然不會
Course you don't.
- 她在手工藝方面非常出色 - 手工藝鍛煉不了膽量
- She's doing really well on handicrafts.  - Handicrafts don't take any nerve.
知道我的意思嗎？格羅根小姐？
Any intestinal fortitude.  You know what that means, Grogan?
- 是的，先生 - 對
- Yes, sir. Guts.  - Right.
有她的信件嗎？
Is there any mail for her?
沒有，堅強些，格羅根小姐
Nope. Skunked again, Grogan.
格羅根.
Grogan.
膽子大一些
Guts.
Uh...
我們走吧，去玩壟斷遊戲
Come on, let's go.  We'll play some Monopoly.
明天早上我們去試一下，好嗎？
Why don't we try it in  an inner tube tomorrow? Huh?
走吧
Come on.
嘿，布蘭迪
Hey, Brandy.
我給你講一個關於狗的故事，它叫菲利普
Did I ever tell you about that  other dog of mine called Philip?
它是一隻非常機靈的狗
Philip grew up in Baltimore with me.
它是一隻好狗
He was a good dog.
它…
He...
有一天它穿過一條街道
He run across the street one day,
它在一輛貨車前面跑過
and he walked right  in front of a trolley car.
貨車壓到了它的尾巴
It ran over his tail. It surprised him.
它感到疼，然後猛一轉身
He turned around and the trolley car...
我在給你講故事呢，然後貨車壓到了它的頭
I'm tellin' you a story. The  trolley car ran over his head.
這個故事有什麼寓意呢？很有趣吧？
It's what you call losin' your head over  a little piece of tail. Pretty funny, huh?
你怎麼了？
What's the matter with you?
你不喜歡我的故事嗎？ 也許你沒理解，反應太快也不是好事
You didn't like the story? Want me  to tell another? Maybe you didn't get it.
這很好玩嗎？
Are you soft in the head?
好的，朋友
OK, my friend.
第一個問題： 那些孩子到底怎麼啦？
Number one:  what happened to those kids?
好的第二個： 你在為軍方幹什麼？
All right, then, try number two: what  were you doin' up at the army site?
- 別這樣做 - 別緊張
- Stop that!  - Oh, he speaks.
嘿
Hey.
- 別把手放進水裡 - 這水怎麼啦？
- Keep your hand out of the water.  - What's wrong with the water?
能告訴我們你的名字嗎？
Since you're talkin' this morning,  buddy, how about a name?
我叫羅伯特.浩克
Hoak. Dr Robert Hoak.
- 水怎麼了？ - 水裡有會吃人的魚
- What's wrong with the water?  - The water is filled with carnivorous fish.
食人魚
Piranha.
哦，我的天
Oh, Christ.
就在這裡面？它們怎麼會在這裡？
In here? How did they get in?
你把池塘水放干的時候，它們就出來了
You let them in when you drained  the pond at the test site.
- 池塘… - 食人魚是熱帶魚
- Paul...  - Piranha are tropical fish.
這裡是冰冷的山區，到這裡它們活不過一分鐘
This is cold mountain water. They  wouldn't last in here for a minute.
那骨架是怎麼回事？
What about that skeleton?
好了，告訴我，為什麼那池塘裡會有食人魚？
OK. What would piranha  be doin' up in that pond?
Huh?
- 還不到時候 - 嘿
- Untie me.  - Hey...
我可以把你扔到水裡
What if I dipped you in  the water a little bit first, Doc?
你明白嗎？
See if you're makin'  the whole thing up or not. Huh?
布蘭迪.
Brandy.
是傑克的狗
That's Jack's dog.
它總是這麼凶嗎？
Is he always so ferocious?
我以前沒看見過它這樣
I don't think I ever heard him do  more than roll over and beg for food.
我們最好過去看看
We'd better take a look.
別緊張，布蘭迪，別緊張
Easy, boy. Easy.
他死前奮力爬到這裡，流血過多而死
He must have dragged himself  this far. Bled to death.
我很難過
I'm sorry.
我去找把鏟子
I'll get a shovel.
他不想被埋在鎮上
He wouldn't wanna be buried in town.
- 就游一次也不行嗎？ - 不行
- Even in an inner tube, huh?  - Uh-huh.
- 不可能會下沉的 - 可它們還是會抓住你的
- It's almost impossible to fall in.  - But they can still get you.
它們？
They, huh?
行，如果你真的是這樣想的話 我會說服他們允許你不參加比賽
OK. lf that's really the way you feel about  it, I'll try and help you get out of the race.
但必須找一個理由，而且不能撒謊
But we've got to come up  with an excuse. Do not lie.
- 我在手工藝製作上拿了名次 - 夏令營還有別人也拿了
- I got poison ivy.  - So does everybody else in the camp.
也許你可以說....不過你還太小了
Hey, maybe you could just be getting  your... No, you're too young for that.
嗯？
Huh?
等一等，我有個主意，跟我來
Wait a minute. I have an idea.  Come with me.
坐這兒
Come here. Sit down here.
你看這個紙箱子，我給你的膝蓋上…
Let's see what we have in our  magic box. Give me your knee.
在比賽之前在大家面前假裝摔一跤
OK. Get Darlene to take  your place in the race. OK?
然後倒在地上呻吟
And if Dumont squawks, limp a lot.
我會給你包紮一個大繃帶
And, uh, I'll get you  a huge bandage for this.
好像是一株水草
Feels like this thing's  snagged on the bottom.
- 把我的網纏繞住了 - 要我幫忙嗎？
- Got myself tangled in it too.  - Want me to help?
不用，你呆在那兒別動，否則小船會翻掉的
No, you better stay there.  You might tip the canoe.
爸爸，你經常這樣抓魚嗎？我說在你小時候
I thought you knew all about this kind  of fishing, from when you were a boy.
我小時候抓魚沒這麼費勁
Listen, when I was a boy we made  our own nets and made 'em right.
越纏越緊了，哇！
Jesus. It feels like  something's snagged in here. Ow!
- 被咬了嗎？ - 啊！
- Did you get bit?  - Ouch!
- 啊！ - 爸爸！
- Ow!  - Dad!
- 呆在那裡！別過來！ - 爸爸！爸爸！
- Stay back! Stay back!  - Dad! Dad!
爸爸！
Dad!
- 政府付你工資嗎？ - 當然付
- The government paid you?  - Of course they paid.
細菌戰武器，炸彈，化學武器
Where there's germ warfare,  the bomb, chemical warfare,
這些都是需要很多錢的，我們是特殊機構
there's plenty of money.  Special agencies.
他們付的錢比我私下做研究賺到的錢多得多
They pay. They pay a lot better  than they do in private research.
就為了養幾條魚
For raisin' fish.
不，是遺傳學
Oh, no. It's a matter of genetics.
用放射性物質進行有選擇的繁殖
Radiation. Selective breeding.
他們把這種研究叫軍用遺傳學
They called it Operation Razorteeth.
那些是幹什麼用的？
What was it all for?
破壞敵人的用水系統
To destroy the river systems  of the North Vietnamese.
我們的目標是繁育出可以在冷水中生存的食人魚
Our goal was to develop a strain of this  killer fish that could survive in cold water
並且能以最快的速度進行繁殖
and then breed at an accelerated rate.
可惜沒能投入應用
We had everything. Blank cheque.
因為戰爭結束了
And then the war ended.
聽你這麼說好像很失望
You sound disappointed.
之後他們在池塘裡放了毒藥
They poisoned the water.
準備把它們都殺死
After all that work,  they poisoned the water.
可是還是有些魚活了下來
But some survived.
我們研究出的變異品種可以抵抗毒藥
We developed a lot of mutants and a few  of them were able to resist the poison.
這些變異品種繁殖能力變得越來越強
They ate their own. Their own dead.
就像是一個新的物種
And then began to breed  like some wild species.
突然之間就有了好幾百條 甚至是幾千條
Suddenly there were hundreds.  Maybe thousands.
- 你的實驗還是很成功的嘛，嗯？ - 這本來是為軍事防衛而設的科學研究
- Our tax dollars at work, huh?  - That's science in the service of defence.
當然現在已經不是了
Sure. Spreadin' strains  of bacteria in the subway system.
它們在河中是會吃人的
You put them in the river where they  could kill people. lncluding civilians.
- 包括平民，以及在河裡游泳的小孩 - 我可沒有殺人
- And kids swimming in the rivers.  - I never killed anybody.
如果有人想殺人那是政府和軍方
If you wanna talk about killing,  talk to your politicians, the military.
不，我是個科學家
No, no. I'm a scientist.
- 河裡的小孩 - 什麼？
- Kids in the water.  - What?
大壩
The dam.
他們每隔幾天就開閘放水一次 以保持湖裡穩定的水量
They let water through every few days  to keep the level steady on the new lake.
大壩下面有度假村和夏令營，小孩們都在那兒，快點
The resort's down there. Summer camp.  All those kids. Come on.
Hey, stop splashin'！
Hey, stop splashin'!
這純粹是個科學研究 可一旦暫時沒有戰爭
It was pure research.  No scrounging for grant money.
這些政客就把資金撤走了 你知道這對於一個科學家的意義
No academic politics. You don't know  what that means to a scientist.
你餵養了它們，你讓它們變異而存活下來
You fed them. You kept them alive.
我私下裡繼續做實驗
I continued the experiment.
對於這個物種我還有很多工作要做
There was so much more  I could do with the species.
它們會變得更有用
So much further I could take them.
你們不會認為我要負全部責任吧？
You're not holding me responsible?
我認為是的  池塘的塞子是你拔掉的 難道要我負全部責任嗎？
I think you are. You pulled the plug and  you're holding me responsible. lncredible.
居然怪到我頭上來了
You're blaming me.
你如果再不閉嘴 我就把這個桿子塞進去
I think if you open your mouth again  I'll stick this pole in it.
- 他們是不是已經把大壩的閘門打開了？ - 我不知道，只希望還沒有
- You think they've opened the dam yet?  - I don't know. We can only hope not.
爸爸
Daddy.
快點
Let's move it.
- 那船在下沉 - 對
- It's sinking, Paul. The canoe is sinking.  - Yeah.
爸爸？
Daddy?
爸爸！爸爸！你在哪兒
Daddy! Daddy! It's going under.
別下水
Don't do it! Get outta there!
快點，瑪吉
Come on, Maggie.
堅持住！堅持
Hold it here. Hold it.
快點！快點！
Come on! Come on! Come here!
快點！抓住我的手
Come on! Give me your hand.
快上船，快把他拉上來
Get the doctor. OK, now the doctor.
放鬆，教授
Easy, Doc.
你不會死的
Here. Here you go.
我們該怎麼辦？該怎麼辦？
What do we do? What do we do?  How do we stop them?
哦，天吶
Oh, Christ.
營員們，該上來吃飯了
Campers. No swinging after lunch.
現在可以確認它們能在冷水中生存了
So far we know that they  can live in cold water.
它們好像是順流而下
They seem to be  moving downstream.
我們必須找到能夠對付它們的人
Gotta find someone who knows  how to deal with these things.
我們得先到大壩到那兒去打電話
There'll be a phone at the dam.  We can call on ahead.
- 嘿 - 怎麼了？
- Hey.  - What?
我不知道是怎麼回事，好像下面有東西在動
I don't know. It seems like  the lashing's workin' loose.
保羅... 下面有東西
Paul... there's something under us.
是血！是血把它們引來的
His blood. It's the doc's blood.
它們在拆船，一點點的咬斷繩子
It's seepin' through. They're eatin'  away at the lashing to get to it.
- 爸爸！ - 不要，我們必須減輕負載
- Daddy!  - Let go, son. No. We gotta get rid of him.
不，我爸爸掉進河裡去了
No. That's what happened to my daddy.
- 快點 - 它們在吃他
- Let go.  - They're eating him.
他們吃掉了他！
They're eating him!
- 過來 - 它們吃了我爸爸！
- Come here.  - They got my daddy!
你沒事吧，孩子？你怎麼樣？
You OK, boy? How about you?
- 我沒事 - 你們待在這兒
- I'm all right.  - You gotta stay here.
我到大壩去，要趕在他們開閘放水之前
I'm gonna try to get to the dam before  they let 'em through with the water.
警告：喇叭聲後隨即開閘放水
Acres and acres of reclaimed land nestled in a scenic mountain valley,
site of the newly formed Lost River Lake.
Swimming, sailing, snorkeling, skin diving, shuffleboard,
and Buck Gardner's Aquarena Amusement Arcade.
So pack up your RVs, your station Wagons, your trailers and cars,
and hustle on up to Lost River Campsite for a free introductory Weekend.
別開閘！ 你說什麼？別開閘！
Don't open it!  Whatever you do, don't open it.
好了，下車集中，快點！
All right, men, off your butts.  Fall in. Move it!
我們對此心存疑慮，因為我們不能每天都能碰到這種事
Forgive our scepticism, but we don't  come across stories like yours every day.
食人魚是熱帶魚種，這裡又不是亞馬遜河
Piranha are warm-water fish.  This is hardly the Amazon.
我告訴你了，這是變異品種 它們已經殺了五個人了
But I told you, these are mutations.  They've already killed five people.
- 是科幻小說吧 - 誘餌準備好了嗎？
- Science fiction.  - You ready with that bait, soldier?
- 是的，長官 - 放吧
- Yes, sir.  - Let her go, son.
據我所知，軍方在山頂確實有個實驗室 不過那在72年就關閉了
Actually, a piranha was caught once  in a pond in Miami, in '72, I believe.
他們已經都把魚毒死了 不會還有什麼食人魚跑到河裡來
But the Fish and Game Commission  poisoned the water, and that was that.
- 這我們都知道 - 有時候會有一些謠言，但…
- That was that, huh?  - The rumours persisted, you know, but...
拉起來
Pull it in, son.
軍事，讓少校準備炸藥
Sergeant, tell the major  to start the pumps.
我們要把它們封鎖在這個河區
We should be able to  contain them in this area.
把河邊的度假村和夏令營都關閉 我們可能會用新型劇毒藥品
Piranha travel in schools, and we've  brought heavy doses of rotenone 235.
- 你確信這些魚能被毒死嗎？ - 這一帶的河水會不會受污染呢？
- Came well-prepared, didn't you?  - Won't it ruin the river?
有的時候僅僅是污染還不夠，還得摧毀
Sometimes you need to destroy  in order to save.
如果它們知道了我們的計劃之後又逆河而上呢？
What if they realise they're  bein' slaughtered and leave?
格羅根先生，我們對付的是魚
We're talking about fish, Mr Grogan.
- 它們不會知道太多的東西 - 等一等，你以為自己在哄小孩嗎？
- They don't realise much of anything.  - Who are you trying to kid?
如果你不知道它們的厲害怎麼會帶這麼多人過來呢？
You must've known  all along they were here.
行了，格羅根先生 現在只有你和這位女士知道它們存在
OK. You and Miss McKeown are the only  two civilians who know about this project.
上校的意思是說 他希望你們能加入我們的隊伍
What the colonel means is that he'd like  you to join us. Become one of our team.
我明白了
It figures.
不可能
Impossible.
你是個上校，對嗎？我肯定你能看懂地圖
Look, you're a full colonel, right?  I assume you can read a map. Here.
我們在大壩，對吧？
We are here at the dam, OK?
再看這兒，這條小溪流入大壩
Over here you'll see there's  a stream that feeds into it.
好，從這條小溪逆流而上大概8公里路 你看這兒有個分岔
Follow the stream back for an eighth  of a mile and you see there's a fork.
從這個小支流，一直向下
Take this branch, follow it downstream,
你會發現水流可以通向大壩的另一頭
and you'll see it empties into the  river on the other side of the dam.
換句話說，這些魚知道怎麼跨越障礙
In other words, the piranha have  a way to get around the obstacle.
如果他是對的，你不覺得應該採取點行動嗎？
Even if there's a chance he's right,  don't you think you should do something?
不，即使支流存在，食人魚也沒有這個耐力和智力
No. lf a bypass exists, piranha haven't  the intelligence or the motivation to find it.
可你沒有聽到浩克說的話，他培養了它們的耐力和智力
But you know Hoak was breeding them  for endurance and intelligence and...
鮑伯是個夢想家
- Well, Bob was a dreamer. He, er...  - Bob?
鮑伯？
Dr Hoak?
你認識他？
You knew him?
魚類研究是一個很小的領域
Fish genetics is a very small field.
你們是朋友嗎？
You were friends?
我們比朋友的關係更密切些
Let's say we were  a great deal more than that.
你在為他隱瞞真相
You're covering up.
你是華克斯曼嗎？你是不是擔心軍隊會除掉你
Is it Waxman? Are you afraid of what  the army might do to you if you...
不是怕，我是科學家，我是我們部門的領導
No, I'm not afraid. I'm a scientist.  I'm head of my department.
是個很重要的部門
It's just that there are priorities, and...
有的東西比幾條人命更重要
some things are more important  than a few lives.
浩克教授可不這麼想
That's not how Dr Hoak felt.  Not at the end.
至少他在生命的最後一刻不是
As I said, he was a dreamer.
- 我剛才說過，他是個夢想家 - 嘿，等等
- The situation is under control.  - Hold on. What is this?
為何你不聽我說呢？
Why won't you listen to me?
你能不能出去一下？
Would you excuse us  for a moment, please?
對於你來說，格羅根先生，這個實驗項目不存在
As far as you're concerned,  this project does not exist.
食人魚不存在，知道嗎？
The piranha do not exist.
- 如果我抗議呢？ - 保羅...
Paul...  - And if I make a squawk?  - Paul...
國家安全部門會被迫採取極端的措施
The interests of national security  permit extreme measures.
得了吧，戰爭已經結束了
Oh, come on! The war's over, dammit!
格羅根先生，還會有別的戰爭
There'll be other wars, Mr Grogan.
我想，為了你們自己的安全 你們呆在帳篷裡，哪兒也別去
I think for your own protection  we'd better secure your tent for the night.
- 出什麼事了嗎？ - 怎麼了？
- Look who's here.  - What's goin' on?
沒事
Nothin'.
他還守著嗎？
Psst! Is he still out there?
對
Yep.
- 你去分散他的注意力 - 為什麼？
- Then you'll have to distract him.  - Why?
- 我可以逃跑 - 你可以逃跑，那我呢？
- So I can get away.  - So you can get away? What about me?
- 隨便，但首先，你要分散他的注意力 - 怎麼分散呢？
- Suit yourself. But first you distract him.  - How?
我怎麼知道？你想辦法讓他背對著帳篷門口，快點
How would I know? Just get him with  his back to the opening. Come on to him.
萬一他是同性戀呢？
What if he's gay?
那就我來分散注意力
Then I'll distract him. Let's go.
嗨
Hi.
嗯
Uh...
今晚真不錯
Nice night, huh?
- 請問，你是同性戀嗎？ - 什麼？
- Listen, are you gay?  - What?
哦
Oh...
我剛才在雜誌上閱讀相關的文章
Well, I was just reading  this article in this magazine, and...
- 你剛才問我什麼？ - 看！天上！
- What did you ask me before?  - Look! Up in the sky!
超人來了！
It's Superman!
哦，糟糕
Oh, shit!
- 怎麼了？ - 身上有五毛錢嗎？
- What's wrong?  - Have you got a dime?
喂？
Hello?
怎麼了？你說什麼？
What? What piranhas?  What are you talking about?
什麼？
What?
你瘋了嗎？是誰啊？
Are you crazy? Who is this?
哦，格羅根，我記起來了，你不是瘋了，你是喝多了
Oh, Grogan. Yeah, I remember you.  You're not crazy, you're drunk.
不，我不想對她說，她和你一樣酩酊大醉
No, I don't wanna talk to her.  I'm sure she's as drunk as you are.
你在那兒等著，我叫警察過來幫你
You wake me up again,  I'll have the cops on you.
什麼？你不能和你女兒談話
What? No, you can't talk to your daughter.
掛了吧，格羅根，我要睡覺！
Sober up, Grogan, and fly right!
食人魚！
Piranhas!
- 混蛋！ - 他不相信你說的
- Asshole!  - He didn't believe you.
- 他以為我喝多了 - 能和你女兒通話嗎？
- He thinks I'm drunk.  - Can you get through to your daughter?
不能，我們得走了
No way. We gotta get down there.
保羅,他們在追我們
Paul, behind us.
這次我們逃不掉了
I know. No way we can  outrun him in this thing.
也許我們可以找他們談一談 可能他們會信我們的
Maybe we can talk to him.  Maybe he'll believe us.
食人魚，嗯？它們從哪兒來的？
Piranha, huh?  And where did they come from?
從山上軍方的試驗池塘裡出來的
From an army test site  up on the mountain.
只有個哨所在那兒，沒有軍隊
That's posted. There's no trespassing.
不是哨所，已經有兩個人在池塘裡死了 河裡又死了四個
Two people were killed up there,  and more along the river.
你必須相信我們
You've gotta believe us.
不大可能吧，你不是叫格羅根嗎？
Now wait. Say, aren't you Grogan?
- 對 - 我記起來了
- Yeah, that's right.  - Uh-huh. I remember.
你上個月喝醉酒開車，我們抓到過你
We had you in on  a drunk and disorderly last month.
可我現在沒醉！你可以對我做酒精測試 請你聽我說好不好？
I am not drunk! You give me a breath test,  whatever you want, only listen to me!
你可以到警察局去測
I think I'm gonna take you up on that,  buddy. Back to the station.
這次你可以好好交代一下了
And you can explain why  you're in an army staff car.
千萬不要動怒，因為我有槍
And don't you get any notion, man,  cos I got my gun in my other hand here.
好嗎？
OK?
我們走，快點
Okey-dokey. Let's go.
我們這兒有情況
Yes. We've got a situation up here.
是非常棘手的情況，你必須幫我控制一下局面
A very delicate situation. And you can  help us control it by holding them for us.
我明白，我會的
Yes, Colonel. Yes, yes.  I understand. We'll do it.
不要讓他們與外面接觸
Make sure they don't  communicate with the outside.
以免引起不必要的麻煩
We're tryin' to avoid unnecessary panic.
當然
Certainly.
為了公眾的利益，我知道
Their best interests, I agree.
遵命
Well, you're welcome, Colonel. Uh...
明早見
See you in the mornin'.
今晚你們得在這兒過夜了，你們好好待著吧
Well, you best make yourself comfortable,  folks. You'll be spending the night.
- 可以打電話嗎？ - 這裡可不行
- What about a phone call?  - I don't wanna hear it.
我不能再讓你們惹出什麼亂子
I don't wanna hear it.
你們還是老老實實呆著
I gotta get back on that road now.
再見了，夥計們，明早見
So you folks, you just behave yourselves.
等一下，你不能就這樣走
No, wait a minute. You can't just leave!
我女兒在那邊！
My daughter's down there!
孩子們還都在河邊！
There are kids down there,  and the piranhas are in the river!
求你了！
Please!
惡魔們散佈在教堂四周
The witch and the demons of the forest  scoured every corner of the church,
毒液從它們的毒牙上直往下滴
venom dripping from their fangs.
巫婆說「你們在哪裡啊？」
"Where is he?" hissed the witch.
惡魔說，把眼皮向上拉
The demons peeled  their heavy eyelids back.
它們來了！
There he is!
There's absolutely no cause for alarm. It's a complete hoax, believe me.
Yeah.
我要提醒你一件事情，可能會出現沒有根據的恐慌
I just wanted to warn you in case  they were able to get a call through.
它會毀了我們隆重的開業慶典
Groundless panic wouldn't help  our grand opening any.
我很感謝你的提醒，我會對我手下的員工們說清楚的
Uh-huh. I really appreciate the warning.  I'll brief my staff. We'll take care of it.
是的，您不用擔心
Yeah. Don't worry.
隨便說一句，明天您過來吧
Uh-huh. By the way,  are you comin' down tomorrow?
很好，很好，您的光臨會給慶典增添光彩
Ah, good. Your presence will lend  a certain prestige to the opening.
Mm-hm.
Huh?
沒人知道這裡有您的投資
No. No, Colonel.  Nobody knows about your investment.
只有另外幾個秘密的合夥投資人
With me, a silent partner's  privacy is sacred.
他們不參與管理，我向您發誓沒人知道
I swear to you on my honour  as a Texan, nobody knows.
是的，將軍
Yes, Colonel.
晚安，晚安
Good night. Good night.
大蠢蛋！
Schmuck!
加點速度，夥計們，我們要在七點之前全部完成
Come on, you guys! Will you haul ass?  This stuff's gotta be set by ten o'clock.
你在那兒幹什麼？
What are you doing back there?
不是抽煙就是喝酒
Hide, that's all they do.  Drink beer and hide.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
我很喜歡這樣的夜晚
I always like it at night.
是啊，我也一樣
Yeah, me too.
一切都沉寂了
It's like it's resting.
- 嘿，想下水游泳嗎？ - 大晚上游泳？
- Hey, wanna race me across?  - To the island?
是啊，我一到這兒就想晚上一個人下水游泳
Yeah. Ever since I got here, I haven't  been able to just swim by myself.
周圍靜悄悄的，感覺真好
I've always had half a dozen  campers hangin' on to me.
我不怎麼喜歡晚上游泳，不過我喜歡看
I don't know. I don't feel like swimming.  But go ahead, I'll watch you.
- 你怕什麼呢？ - 我不知道
- What's the matter?  - I don't know.
有些事情…有些事情不太對勁
Something... Something's wrong.
來吧，和我一塊兒下水吧，對身體有好處的
Come on, come with me.  It'll do you some good.
- 也許你是對的 - 行了，我們下水吧
- You're probably right.  - Good. OK.
格羅根夫人，你們在幹什麼！
Grogan, turn off that flashlight!
別害怕，就我一個人
Don't be alarmed - it's only me.
有謠言說夏令營裡有人半夜三更到這兒來游泳
There's a rumour some campers  are coming for a midnight swim.
如果被我抓住的話她們就慘了
If I catch them swimming, they'll be  in pretty hot water, I can tell you.
- 那麼剛才在幹什麼？ - 我們只是…
- What are you doing out here?  - Oh, well, we...
我們剛才好像聽見有營員來游水
I thought I heard some campers  swimming. We came down to look.
- 游泳？在哪兒？ - 在瀑布邊
- Swimming? Where?  - Over by the waterfall.
瀑布邊？是在那邊嗎？
The waterfall?  Is that where they're doing it?
那是什麼？
- What was that?
是湖的那邊游泳的人發出的聲音
It sounded like campers  on the other side of the lake.
湖的那邊？
The other side of the lake?
多謝，給我上來，你們…
Thank you. Kim Burrell, is that you?
看來只好等到明天了
Well, there's always  tomorrow for that swim.
是啊，明天再說吧
Yeah. Let's do it tomorrow.
- 你在幹什麼？ - 有人教過我一招，我想用一下
- What are you doin'?  - Did I tell you about Mo Schneider?
- 是誰？ - 以前認識的一個越獄慣犯
- Who's that?  - This guy they sent me to find one time.
他是個水管工，他以不雅的身體暴露被拘留了
He was a plumber. He kept running off  and getting busted for indecent exposure.
嘿，你在那兒幹什麼？
What are you doin' there?
因為行為不檢點，他被拘留多次
Mo was in the poky so many times that  he developed a regular escape routine.
逃跑的技巧越來越高，這是一個水管工的絕招
Being a plumber,  he used what he knew best.
怎麼回事？
What the hell was that?
你在幹什麼？你沒事吧？
What are you doing? Are you all right?
老天！聽著…
Christ, listen.
你這個計劃會有用嗎？
This, uh, this plan,  whatever it is, did it ever work?
你一會就知道了
No. But he came pretty  close a couple of times.
只要看門的人會進來
Pretty damn close.
怎麼回事？聽起來像是天花板掉了 滿地的水是怎麼回事？
What's all that racket? Sounds like the  roof fell in. What's all this water from?
管道洩露了
Something's leaking,  and I'll catch pneumonia if it doesn't stop.
- 那水管子怎麼了？ - 我試了好幾次
- What's the matter with that sink trap?  - I've tried,
可是力氣不夠放不回去
but I'm just not strong enough  to put the pipes back together.
你往後退，我進來看看
All right. Stand back, I'll take a look at it.
這是怎麼回事？是出水管的問題嗎？
What the hell did you do to this thing?  Tryin' to crawl through the drainpipe?
- 怎麼了？發生什麼事了？ - 他只是暈過去了，還活著
- What's happenin'?  - He's knocked out, but he's alive.
快拿鑰匙，有鑰匙嗎？
Get his keys. Can you get his keys?
- 與褲子繫在一起 - 那麼把褲子脫下來吧
- They're chained to his pants!  - Well, take his pants off, then.
你脫男人褲子不會這麼慢吧？
Come on. I'd have thought you could  get a man's pants off quicker than that.
好了，我拿到了！
Got 'em! I got 'em!
好，我們走
Come on. Let's go.
- 你用什麼打的他？ - 一個水龍頭
- What did you hit him with?  - A piece of the toilet lid.
- 這次可又是我的功勞啊 - 感謝你的那個暴露狂師傅
- Maybe I should have tried bribery first.  - Thank you, Mo Schneider.
你真是他的好學生
Don't suppose one of those  keys would fit a patrol car?
我們又自由了
I wouldn't be surprised.
歡迎今天來的所有客人
Howdy, folks. I'm Buck Gardner.
謝謝大家
Thank you.
謝謝，謝謝大家
Thank you. I appreciate that.
這個大家等待已經久的度假村
On behalf of Buck Gardner's  Aquarena Development Corporation,
今天終於開張了
it gives me great pleasure to invite you  here to our opening-day festivities.
這個地區是非常引人入勝的，我們有眾多娛樂節目
If you have any questions about  purchasing land up here,
大家可以盡情享受
our people will be mingling in the crowd  to answer your questions.
沒有必要買任何東西 大家只管玩就行了
You got no obligation to buy anything,  only to enjoy yourselves. Annie?
來吧
Right there.
剪吧
再試試
Try again.
剪的真好，孩子
Nice try, kid.
行了！
That's it!
不要忘了，我們有免費燒烤，中午一點鐘開始
Don't forget, free barbecue  this afternoon at one o'clock.
大家盡情享受吧
Enjoy yourselves.
蠻成功的
We got 'em.
別看了！只看不練的小鬼
No comics! No comics. No discipline.
水上競賽時間到了，大家放下弓箭
Water competition.  Muster up. Water competition.
換上游泳衣到河邊去
Put the arrows away.  Put the bows in the tep...
這不好笑
That isn't funny.
快來！快
Minnows, over here!
快點兒，孩子們
Come on, kids.
快點，你們這些小傢伙
Come on, you guys.
孩子們，到這兒來，孩子們，快過來，快點
Guppies! Come on, let's go!  Come on, line up. That's right. Come on.
過來排隊，大家站好
Standing in line. Straight line.
分成兩隊，我們來高呼，我們一定贏
Straighten up. OK. We're gonna  have a tube race. Who's gonna win?
- 一定能贏 - 一定能贏！
- Minnows!  - We are!
我們要贏！
We are!
好啦，你們這些傢伙
All right. OK, you guys.
游泳是不能戴眼鏡的，給我
You cannot swim with your glasses on.
兩人一組，手拉手
Let's turn this way now.  Buddy system. Arms up.
就這樣，很好
There we go. Stand up straight. Come on.
- 站直了 - 真不錯，你就像是一條小孔雀魚
- Stand up straight.  - Come on, be proud you're a Guppy.
很好，很好
That's good. That's good.  Hold your stomach in.
早上好，營員們，找準你們自己的伴兒
Morning, campers.  Fall in back here and buddy up.
杜蒙特先生，我們已經準備好了
Mr Dumont, we're ready for you, sir.
把手放下！
Arms down!
現在我們要看看誰是兔子，誰是烏龜
All right now. This is where we separate  the tortoises from the hares,
誰會像下沉的木頭，誰才是真正的游泳健將
the wheat from the chaff,  and the sinkers from the swimmers.
水是鹹的
Salt water.
- 什麼？ - 我記得水是鹹的
- What?  - I just remembered. It was salt water.
- 什麼時候？ - 試驗湖的池塘裡
- What was?  - ln the pond at the test site.
- 我差點忘了 - 那又怎樣？
- I thought it was strange, then I forgot.  - So?
而食人魚是淡水魚，這就是說，浩克開發出來的魚種
Piranha are freshwater fish.  Hoak must have developed a strain
在鹹水和淡水都能存活，和大馬哈魚一樣
that can live both in fresh and salt.  Like salmon.
- 所以它們想進入大海 - 它們會進入大海嗎？
- That's why they headed downstream.  - And if they get to the ocean?
它們沒別的目標，它們將游經整個國家的河流
There'll be no way to contain 'em. They'll  be able to swim up every river system.
你在幹什麼？你應該下水游泳
What are you doing?  You should be in that race.
- 可媽媽說… - 我不要聽任何理由
- But Betsy told me...  - I don't want to hear any excuses.
- 換上泳衣，老老實實過去 - 可我的膝蓋
- Get a tube and get out there.  - But I hurt my knee.
值得懷疑，營員！
On the double, camper!
聽著，孩子們，聽著！
Listen up, you kids!
我們馬上就要開始比賽了
We're gonna start  the tube race in a minute.
兩一組接力賽！
Kathryn! McCarthy! MacBride!
全部過來集中一下
All you campers, come in here.  You're too far out.
混蛋，怎麼開車的
Goddamn Sunday driver.
預備？
Ready?
加油啊！夥計們
Come on! This is a race, people!
賈可布森，再快一點，帕金森，加油啊
Jacobson, put a little muscle in it!  Parkinson, a little effort!
孩子們，使出你們的解數吧！
Kids, let's get a little leg action!
怎麼回事？
What's the matter?
那是什麼？
What is that?
- 蘇珊 ！ 蘇珊 ,快回去，回去啊 - 快上船
- Suzie! Suzie, no. Go back! Go back!  - Get on the boat.
貝琪 ！
Betsy!
蘇珊 ！
Suzie!
爸爸
Daddy!
那兒有電話，你給度假村打電話
There's a phone in there. Call the resort  and warn 'em. I'll get the kids out.
接線生，給我阿普裡那溫泉度假村的電話
Operator, get me the number  of the Aquarena Springs Resort.
查電話號碼簿
Look in the phone book.
慢慢享用，請隨意，今天的一切都是免費的
Enjoy yourself. Enjoy yourself.  Everything's free today. Enjoy yourself.
祝你玩的開心
Keep 'em moving, Terry.
孩子，到一邊玩去
Wrong away, kid. This is the exit.
- 嘿，寶貝 - 加德納先生，有你的電話
- Hey, baby.  - Mr Gardner? Mr Gardner?
- 是誰？ - 她說非常重要
- What is it?  - Real important.
- 我是加德納 - 現在聽我說
- Buck Gardner.  - Now listen to me.
這不是玩笑電話 有緊急情況
This is not a crank call.  I am completely serious.
緊急情況？
Emergency?
別緊張，別緊張
Easy. Easy.
我抱住你了
I got you. I got you.
沒事了
All right.
求你了，你一定要相信我說的
Please. Please, you've gotta believe me.
- 謝謝你 - 聽我說，求你了…
- Thank you.  - Listen to me! Please, before it's...
謝謝你，食人魚
Thank you. Piranha.
- 和同伴手牽手  - 我們要去另外一個地方
- They're sending an ambulance.  - We gotta drive to the resort ourselves.
- 你自己能頂住嗎？ - 我沒事
- Can you handle this?  - Uh, yeah. I think so.
親愛的，我們很快就回來
Honey, I'll be back  for you real soon, I promise.
呆在這兒好嗎？
So you be brave, huh? Help out here?
真是我的好女兒
That's my girl.
沒事的，蘇珊
It's OK, Suzie.
他們會回來的
He'll be back.
這片海岸到處都可以游泳，去吧
We got plenty of targets.  Yes, sir. Right over there.
順便問一下，先生
By the way, sir, they've noticed.
有個女人說，你曾經在佛羅里達一艘潛艇裡工作
One woman recognised  the submarine ride from Florida.
這個國家什麼地方我沒去過
Of course she did.  I picked it up second-hand.
屠宰場，軍隊都留下了我的足跡
Skyway's from Redondo Beach.  Boathouse is army surplus.
紅鶴是從愛達荷州弄來的
Dancing chickens?  From a carnival in ldaho.
天鵝是從亞特蘭大弄來的
Ralph the Swimming Swine?  From Atlantic City.
看來你這個度假村的東西都是一流的
They're saying, for a new resort,  nothing's looking very new.
那當然，那些都是國家一級保護動物
What do they know? Ralph the Swimming  Swine's practically a national monument.
不過我不光是為了賺錢，是為了讓大家玩的開心點
He's been swimming for  more years than I can remember.
你看這種建築對大眾有什麼作用？
The other stuff they just don't make. That  submarine ride is a piece of Americana.
是的
Yes, sir.
- 可用的卻是大家的錢 - 我不知道
- Maybe they never heard of recycling.  - I don't know.
笑一個，我們還有活動，你好，參議員
Smile, we're goin' public.  Hello, Senator. How are you?
如果媒體知道，我們倆都完了
If they get to the media,  we're both screwed.
華克斯曼上校，梅克斯博士，歡迎你們的光臨
Colonel Waxman. Dr Mengers.  What a pleasant surprise.
他們逃跑了
They busted jail.
- 他們已經打過電話來了 - 你的手下都準備好了嗎？
- They already called.  - Is your staff ready?
我想您能不能給您在本地媒體機構的熟人打個電話
- They're all set.  - Call your local newspaper.
讓他們不要大肆宣傳這件事
Warn 'em they might get  some crank calls.
- 讓他們把信息封鎖一段時間 - 你知道該怎麼做，趕快去
- Wouldn't it be better...  - You got your orders. Hop to it.
上校，那些謠言我已經聽到了 我知道該怎麼處理
Cool it with the military crap.  I'll take care of it.
跟我走，我馬上去辦
Whitney? Let's hop to it.
- 華克斯曼上將，好久不見了 - 是上校，夫人
- General Waxman, it's been so long.  - It's Colonel, ma'am.
還是上校嗎？為什麼？
Colonel, still? Oh, I can't imagine why.
政治需要，夫人，政治需要
Politics, ma'am. Politics.
笨蛋一個
Stupid cow.
- 準備好了嗎？ - 好了
- Ready?  - OK.
嘿，他滑的可真不賴
Hey, he really does ski great.
- 他在表現他自己 - 他總這樣
- He's such a show-off.  - He thinks he's such hot shit.
- 也許我們可以再開快點 - 好
- Maybe we're not going fast enough.  - I can fix that.
等一下！那兒有什麼東西
Hold it! There's something back here!
停下！馬上停下
Take it in! Now!
- 嘿，好像有問題啊 - 是啊，他有點吃不消了
- I think something's wrong.  - Yeah, we haven't dumped him yet.
停下！
Stop!
有情況！那裡有問題，快點！停下它
Take me in! There's something in here!  Come on! Get me outta here!
減速，停下
Slow down. Stop!
加速，別停下
Faster! Don't stop!
- 等等，他到底… - 不！
- Wait. He says...  - No!
加速，快加速
Speed up. Speed up!
停下！
Stop!
啊！啊！ 啊！
Argh! Argh! Argh!
糟了！
Dammit!
沒有，波比，一切正常
No, Bob. It's completely false.
你應該相信我
There's not a word  of truth to it, believe me.
- 先生 - 我在接電話
- Sir?  - I'm on the phone!
食人魚
Piranhas.
- 不是說了別相信這東西 - 但是食人魚…
- Don't even say that word!  - But the piranhas...
- 食人魚怎麼啦？ - 食人魚在吃我們的客人
- What about the piranhas?  - They're eating the guests, sir.
哦...
Uh...
鮑伯，我要回去了，這邊出了點小問題
Bob, I'm gonna have to get back to you on  this. We've got a... a situation down here.
快點，快上來！
Come on. Get off! You'll tip us over.
上來！
Get off!
該死，快上來！
Dammit, get off!
我們去哪兒？
Where are we going?
我原來那個工廠的排水口
The lake narrows where  the outlet for the refinery was.
在冶煉爐裡還有很多廢水
They'll be bunched tight  when they come through there.
然後呢？
What then?
如果那些廢水還在的話，我們去把它們放出來
If it isn't tapped off, there might be  enough waste left in the smelting tanks.
- 可以殺了食人魚嗎？ - 可以毒死一切
- It'll kill the fish?  - It'll kill anything.
把食人魚一網打盡
We'll pollute the bastards to death.
哦，老天，不
Oh, Lord. No.
- 怎麼了？ - 漲潮了
- What's wrong?  - It's all flooded.
控制室被淹了
The control booth is underwater.
- 怎麼辦？ - 我們得想想辦法
- What can we do?  - Well, we gotta do somethin'.
- 拖繩在哪兒？ - 在後面
- Where's that towline?  - It's in the back.
我要你開始慢慢的計數，一直數到100
So I want you to start  counting slowly up to 100.
然後，不管我有沒有浮出水面，你加速，把我拉出來
Then, whether I'm up to the surface or  not, hit that throttle and get outta here.
不是說那時候肯定事情已經做好了 而是我只能憋那麼久的氣
If I'm not up by then, I'm in trouble, cos  that's as long as I can hold my breath.
好，開始計數吧
So, let's count it down together.
- 好嗎？ - 好吧
- OK?  - Yeah.
- 1！ - 1！
- One. - One.
2！
Two.
- 3！ - 3！
- Three. - Three.
- 4！ - 4！
- Four. - Four.
5！
Five.
6！
Six.
7！
Seven.
48！
48.
49！
49.
63！
63.
64！
64.
82！
82.
83！
83.
98！
98.
99！
99.
100！
100.
保羅！
Paul!
迷失河之湖 充滿著恐怖與死亡
Lost River Lake.  Terror, horror, death. Film at 1 1 .
- 快來人！ - 幫幫忙！
- Medic!  - Help!
你還在拍什麼？還拍什麼啊？
What the hell are you filming?  What the hell are you filming?!
喝一點吧
Try and take some.
給我們介紹一下情況吧，梅克斯博士
Where do we go from here, Dr Mengers?
我們要先進行調查，看應該由誰負責
I'm personally going to head  a full-scale investigation into this incident,
以避免類似的事情再次發生
to discover who was responsible, and  to ensure this could never happen again.
這些食人魚對海洋的生態環境有影響嗎？
As an expert in tropical species,  what danger is there in the possibility of the piranha reaching the ocean?
沒有，現在已經不用擔心了
Oh, none. Most of them Will have  been destroyed by pollution at the lake.
這些魚無法在鹽水中生活
If any did get through, there's no Way  they could survive the salt Water.
現在沒有食人魚了
There's nothing left to fear.